All the food's gonna go bad.
Yeah, I drew up a list.
I'll hit the store before
it gets all bought out.
Fuck.
Can you save it?
No, no way.
No, I gotta start over from scratch.
I'll call the studio when
the phones get back up,
see if they can extend my deadline.
What choice do they have?
You kiddin'? They could whip up
some bad Photoshop poster in an afternoon.
They do it all the time, two big heads.
I should've brought it downstairs
with me last night,
I was just stupid, I guess.
Well, sweetie, you couldn't exactly know
that a tree was gonna come
flying through the window.
Yeah, I'll hit the hardware store too,
get some plastic sheeting and duct tape
and seal this up before
it gets dark, you know.
Order in some new glass.
Aw, you know what?
That was your grandfather's tree,
the one he planted.
I used to play in that tree.
It's just stuff though.
You know, we're safe,
that's all that counts.
Yeah.
Mom, Dad, you gotta come see!
Hey, Billy, take it easy, all right?
I really don't want you
running all over the place.
But you gotta come look!
The boathouse is all bashed.
Holy crap!
Billy!
Sorry, Mom,
but you just gotta come, come on.
Come on!
Having spoken, the Doomsayer departs.
How do you two always manage
to make me laugh?
You have incredibly low standards.
All right, let's go see the damage.
No!
- Norton's tree.
- Yeah.
You mean the dead one I've been asking him
to take down for three years
before it finally blew over?
That tree?
It really got smooshed.
You ain't kiddin'.
Look at that.
What is it, Daddy?
Mist?
- On the lake?
- We've had mist on the lake before.
Coming off the mountain like that?
Two fronts meeting,
leftover from the storm?
Something like that?
- You sure?
- Honey, I'm not the weatherman.
Why don't you take Billy, get him dressed?
I'll take him to town with me.
All right. Where you goin'?
I'm gonna go have a little chat
with our neighbor about his tree.
Hon.
Don't worry, I'm not gonna
punch him in the nose.
You know what he's gonna say.
He's gonna say "Sue me,"
which, I don't know, maybe we should.
Honey, one property dispute with this guy
is enough to last me a lifetime.
I'm gonna ask for
his insurance information.
- Okay.
- That's all.
Yeah.
Motherfucker!
Aw, shit!
You motherfucker!
Cocksucker!
"Turn on,
full choke,
pull five,
choke."
I guess you've seen the...
Boathouse.
Yeah, and?
Nothin'.
Just think we should trade insurance info,
you know?
That's all.
My insurance guy's gonna love me.
Shit.
The 1980.
I was gonna bring the station wagon,
but, I don't know,
the weather was so beautiful
coming out of New York, I just...
You know, top down.
I'm sorry, man, I mean it.
Sincerely.
That's nice of you to say.
No, that car was cherry.
I hate to see it like that.
Okay, I'll tell you what.
I'll find my insurance guy's number,
I'll bring it by later.
- Is that okay?
- No problem.
So, David.
You're not heading into town
today by any chance, are you?
Well, CMP's out in force.
- Maybe we'll get our power back.
- That was some storm, huh?
One for the books, yeah.
For a moment there last night
I thought we were gonna
take off and head for Oz.
WZON is off the air,
but Portland's still broadcasting.
Daddy, look!
Guys from the base.
From up the mountain?
The Arrowhead Project?
Well, you're a local.
Any idea what they do up there?
Missile defense research, you know,
I'm sure you've heard the stories.
Sure. The woman at the Laundromat says
that they have a crashed flying saucer
up there with frozen alien bodies.
Right, Miss Edna, yeah.
Miss Tabloid.
"I Had Bigfoot's Baby."
"Satan's Face Appears in Oil Well Fire."
You know, real reliable stuff.
They're in a hurry.
Maybe their power's out too.
Still no signal.
Why don't you go ahead?
I'm gonna try Steff on the pay phone.
Can I go with Mr. Norton, Daddy?
Sure, if you promise
to hold his hand, I guess.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Here's a list.
- Okay.
- Okay?
Meet you guys in there.
Hold hands.
I'm sorry,
I didn't know it was your sister.
...looks so freaky.
- Sally, hey. You guys look jammed up.
- Hey, Mr. Drayton.
Yeah, well, half the staff didn't show,
plus the power's out.
Oh, no. What, no backup generator?
Only to keep the food cold.
Everything else, welcome to the Dark Ages
and bring your checkbook.
Hey, Thursday night,
Steff and I want a date night.
- Babysit?
- Heck yeah, I'm there.
Oh, my God.
The storm.
Everybody's stocking up,
been like this since we opened.
Crappy day, huh?
Everyone's a little pissed off
this morning.
Morning, Mrs. Carmody.
With lines like these,
I don't know how good it is,
but I guess we'll have to make do.
Keep your head down, pal.
I know it.
Hey, champ.
Your wife should be a doctor.
She could make a fortune in Manhattan
with this handwriting.
Yeah, it takes some getting used to.
Why don't you get your stuff?
I'll meet you at the checkout.
Okay, done.
Hey, David.
Thanks for helping me out today.
Are you and Mr. Norton
gonna be friends now, Daddy?
I don't know.
Friends might be stretching it a little.
Guess you're not mad
at each other anymore.
I guess not.
Hey, and that's a start, eh?
I'm sorry, ma'am, the register's down.
The power outage got us too.
Hopefully we'll have power up pretty soon.
I asked.
I asked for just a little something.
The bus leaves in 30 minutes.
We'll make it, okay?
You guys get the goodies,
I'll wait in line.
I need some change on register 5.
Good morning, Ms. Reppler.
Hello, Ms. Reppler.
Well, hello to you, Billy Drayton.
How'd you hold up in the storm?
We had a tree come through
the picture window last night,
right in my studio.
And the boathouse got all smooshed.
Mr. Norton's tree fell on it.
Ouch.
Sorry to hear that.
Well, how'd you guys make out?
We're fine.
It's the listings I'm worried about.
At the very least, I'll bet every one
of our "For Sale" signs fell over.
We had damage at the school,
wouldn't you know?
That's what we get for
not fixing that roof when we should've.
But with funds being cut every year,
you'd think educating children
would be more of a priority
in this country,
but you'd be wrong.
Government's got better things
to spend our money on,
like corporate handouts
and building bombs.
Daddy, is there a fire?
Is Mommy all right?
I'm sure she's fine. Don't worry, okay?
Mind what you're doing, Sally.
Come on, we've got 10 days leave.
Check our papers.
Look, I told you, all leaves are canceled.
I don't know why.
I gotta go check the pharmacy out.
Three men meet me back
at the jeep in 5 minutes.
That's an order.
Shit, man.
Another half an hour, we'd have been gone.
Oh, my God.
Something in the mist!
Something in the mist took John Lee!
Dan, catch your breath!
Something in the mist took John Lee.
I could hear him screaming.
Shut the doors! Shut the doors, my God!
Daddy, I'm scared. Can we go home?
Don't go out there.
There's something in the mist.
It took John Lee!
Screw that, I'm getting in my car.
Mister, no!
Please hold me.
It's okay, it's okay.
It's a pollution cloud,
from the mills, down in Rumsford.
Some kind of chemical explosion,
has to be.
What is it?
What's going on?
It's death.
Subtitle | www.movieddl.me
Daddy!
That was an earthquake.
I tell ya, the goddamn mills blew up!
Is everyone okay?
Is anyone hurt?
Everybody just stay put, okay?
Just stay inside the store.
I can't.
I can't stay here.
I gotta get home to my kids.
No, no, don't go out there.
It's death out there.
It's the end of days.
Stop it, okay? Stop it.
Please, everybody,
everybody just relax. Okay?
He's right. Let's just stay cool.
Let's just try to figure out
what happened.
I'm sorry.
I can't just stay here.
I have to get home to my kids.
Ma'am, no, you can't go out there.
- That could be a poisonous gas cloud.
- Didn't you hear that man screaming?
I agree. Let's stay here
until we figure it out.
You're not listening!
I can't stay here.
Wanda's looking after little Victor.
She's only 8.
Sometimes she forgets she's supposed to
be watching him, you know?
I told them I'd only be gone
a few minutes.
She's only 8!
For their sakes, don't.
Well, is anybody gonna help me?
It's okay, pal.
Won't somebody here see a lady home?
You?
It's okay, buddy.
- You?
- Ma'am, please.
I got my own boy to worry about.
I hope you all rot in hell.
- Ma'am, please, wait until--
- Get off of me.
Okay, let's start cleaning up, okay?
Get the spilled bottles,
broken glass, stuff like that.
Aisle 3 has medical supplies.
Okay, okay, it's okay.
Easy champ, come on.
All right, hey, hey, hey.
You can't keep crying like this, pal.
Come on.
You're gonna hurt yourself.
Come on, you all right?
I want Mommy.
All right, I know you do. Okay.
Just try to breathe, okay?
Just try to breathe, pal, it's okay.
It's all right.
I haven't seen him
suck his thumb like this
since he was two years old.
He's in shock.
I think we all are.
You haven't met.
Amanda Dunfrey.
She's new in town as of this semester.
Teaches 3rd grade,
and the Special Ed kids
now that Mosher's retired.
She's wonderful, the kids love her.
And David's an artist,
he does movie posters and such.
And me.
Lord, I'm babbling away
like some old biddy at a tea party.
My nerves are jangled, I guess.
Boy settle down?
How is he?
Still hot.
Why don't I get him some aspirin?
Aisle 3.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
How's Dan?
His nose stopped bleeding.
He's calmer now,
somebody gave him a Valium.
I can't believe the way he ran in here.
Never seen him like that.
I need something to cover my boy up.
You got any blankets?
Furniture pads, loading dock.
Gonna keep checking on people,
if you need anything, just holler.
You bet. Sally, you mind?
I'd love to.
I really should help him clean up.
I'll take him.
- Okay.
- Daddy, don't go!
No, I'll be gone two seconds, Big Bill.
Come on, I'm gonna get your blanket.
Mrs. Reppler's here,
and so is Mrs. Turman.
I'll be close by, okay?
Don't worry, I'm not far. Okay?
Let me look at you.
Wanna lie down?
Yeah.
There you go.
As soon as it blows away,
we can walk out of here safe and free,
but we have to be smarter.
The first thing we need to do
is keep our wits about us
and find out what's happening.
Well, how we gonna do that, my man?
We've got no phone signal.
We've got no radio.
I'm sure they're working on
those problems as we speak.
It stands to reason that
restoring communications
would be their top priority.
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Goddamn it!
Bitch!
It's obvious that we're in
some kind of natural disaster here.
Ain't nothing obvious about
this son of a bitch from where I sit.
There ain't nothing natural
about it either.
That's right.
It's Judgment Day,
and it's come round at last.
There is nothing more obvious
or natural than that.
Aw, fuck now.
You've done that to yourself
by a life of sin and disillusion.
- Hey, whoa!
- David!
Hey, you guys hear that?
The generator?
We're just gonna check it out.
No, no, I turned the generator off,
it was backing up.
Nobody else heard that sound?
What sound?
I don't know, like a weird noise,
back there in the dark.
Like something was
pressing against the door.
Did you hear it
before the lights went out or after?
No, only after.
After, but look, I heard it, okay?
Nobody's calling you a liar.
That's what it sounds like.
No, no, no, no, now
don't be that way, Mr. Drayton.
You had a scare, no doubt.
Let's say we all go check it out.
Here.
Man.
It's pretty rank in here.
Myron, go check it out.
All right.
Go on, fire it up.
All right, turn it off!
Holy crow, don't that stink.
Something's got the exhaust vent
plugged up from the outside.
You get it running long enough
to raise that door a little,
I'll go out and clear
whatever's blocking it.
- No, no, you can't do that.
- Why not?
It's an electric door, right?
Well, yeah, but it may not be wise
to send him out there.
Okay, I'll do it.
No, look, it's not about
who goes out there--
What, don't you think I can do it?
Hey, I want to go, it was my idea.
Whoa, wait, wait, just stop, okay?
Jim, right?
Myron?
You guys are...
Well, you don't seem to understand,
or you're trying real hard not to.
This isn't an ordinary mist, okay?
You open that door and
something gets in here--
Like what?
Well, like whatever made
that noise I heard.
Are you guys being willfully dense?
Mr. Drayton, you know, pardon me,
but I'm not convinced
that you heard anything.
I mean, we're not hearing
anything now, right?
Anybody?
See?
Now, I know, I know,
you're a big shot artist
with connections in New York
and Hollywood and all that,
but that don't make you
better than anybody else,
- not in my book.
- Hey, I didn't say that.
Nor do I like being talked down to
or called stupid
by a guy who went to college
just 'cause he's got the jitters.
Fellas, it doesn't even
matter about the generator,
the food will keep without it.
Kid, I'm gonna start the motor,
you raise the door,
and you yell out when you got enough room.
Yeah. Okay, good.
Wait!
You guys are gonna
let this kid risk his life
over a generator that doesn't even matter?
- Would you just shut the fuck up already?
- Norm!
Listen, Mr. Drayton, I tell you what.
The next time you got something to say,
you count your teeth.
Because I'm sick to death
of your bullshit.
All right?
- Come on, Myron.
- This is crazy!
Leave 'em be.
What am I,
impugning their manhood or something?
Listen, they've lost
their sense of proportion.
What's going on here?
Out there in the market
they were scared and confused.
In here, there's a problem they can solve.
So, they're goddamn gonna solve it.
- Ready, kid?
- Let's rock!
Norm, come on.
Don't, man.
It's a mistake.
Pussy.
Hold up!
So, any boogeyman?
Pretty scary, ain't it, Norm?
Yeah, right.
Norm.
Norm!
What the fuck?
Get it off, get it off!
Get this friggin' thing off me!
Get it off!
Help me, help me, help me!
There's more. There's more!
Somebody help me.
What the fuck are you waiting for?
Hang on!
Hold him still!
Jesus...
Shit, shit!
Shit!
Dave, it's no good!
Start the generator!
Shit!
Hey, I'm sorry.
But how the hell was I supposed
to know what you meant?
You said you heard something.
How was I supposed to know what you meant?
You should've said what you meant better.
I don't know, I thought maybe
it was a big bird or something.
You got that kid killed.
Did you get a good look at it, huh?
Did you get a good look at what you did?
Huh?
David! Don't hit him anymore!
- And you too! Assholes!
- It doesn't solve anything.
You got that kid killed,
and I got his fucking blood on me!
Okay, I'm done.
Okay.
What's next?
Kill the generator.
That's the first thing.
I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ. Oh, God.
I'm sorry about the kid.
Oh, God. Oh, God. Oh, God.
We oughta get outta here.
Hey, man, we didn't twist this on him.
Yeah, he's a fuckin' kid.
He's supposed to be stupid.
What's your excuse, huh?
Get outta here.
Go back in the market, stay by the door.
Don't say anything to anybody.
Not yet.
Shit.
David?
Need a little light here.
We have to tell 'em.
The people in the market,
we have to stop them from going outside.
They won't believe us.
They have to.
I'm not sure I believe it. I was here.
What we saw was impossible.
You know that, don't you?
I mean, what do we say?
How do we convince them?
Ollie, what the hell were those tentacles
even attached to?
Oh, my God. Are you all right?
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
it's not my blood, I'm fine.
What the hell happened?
I'll explain. Give me a minute, okay?
I need to deal with something first.
Please, I've got to...
I can't let Billy see me like this,
he's scared enough.
Just give me a minute,
keep him distracted.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Hey, look.
I'm sorry about Norm.
Me too.
I mean, I ain't making excuses,
I'm just saying.
Look, we need to tell people.
We don't need to say how it went down
or anything like that,
but we're in the deep shit here.
People need to know.
What about the out-of-towners?
We've got plenty of them in the store.
- Where do we even start?
- Brent Norton?
That windbag?
He's an important attorney in New York.
That fella could be on the bench one day.
Counts a lot for people
in this town, or anywhere.
- Yeah, that's right.
- Do it quick, David.
We've gotta discuss how we're gonna
stop that thing getting in here.
Wait, what do you mean getting in?
You shut the loading door.
Yeah, but the entire front
of the store is plate glass.
Jesus Christ.
Listen.
That guy who came in here
with the bloody nose.
They're, they're...
We saw tentacles.
It ain't going very well, is it?
- You what?
- Come here.
Come here.
Tell him.
It's true.
Tentacles. Yeah.
Gentlemen, I'm sorry,
I'm just not that stupid.
I mean, what do you take me for?
I'm shocked.
I'm shocked. I'm shocked.
It's pretty tasteless
using what's happening here
to try to make me look like an idiot.
No, no, no,
that's not what's going on here.
Look, come back to the loading dock,
okay? I'll show you.
Blood, and a chuck of tentacle
on the floor.
- No.
- No? What do you mean no?
No. We've got real problems
to deal with here,
and this pathetic attempt at a joke
has gone far enough.
Mr. Norton.
- What reason could we possibly have--
- Please, please!
This is payback for the lawsuit
that I filed against him last year,
and you guys are backing him up.
So, winning wasn't enough, huh?
You wanted to humiliate me some more.
Show me a rubber snake while these hicks
stand around laughing their asses off.
- Watch who you're calling a hick.
- Myron, Myron!
- Hey, hey, fuck--
- Mr. Norton, I swear.
You've got us all wrong.
You're not too crazy
about out-of-towners, are ya?
I only spend my money
and I pay my taxes here,
and I've seen you talking behind my back.
How y'all stick together?
Well, don't I feel foolish?
I actually thought you were
being kind to me today.
Well, thanks for setting me straight.
And I'm glad that tree fell
on your boathouse, you know that?
Glad. Smashed it in pretty good,
didn't it? Fantastic.
Now all of y'all, just stay out of my way-
I know you're scared, man. I'm scared too.
Lives are at stake around here.
- David, I--
- Okay, my son's life.
Now, I need you.
Brent, please,
get your head out of your ass. All right?
I'll drag you back there if I have to.
Come here.
- David, get your--
- No, I need--
Get your goddamn hands off of me!
I'll sue your ass again! Sue your ass!
And this time you'll go to jail.
This man assaulted me.
He assaulted me. You were witness to it.
- This man's crazy, he's crazy.
- No.
He isn't. I wish he was, but he isn't.
Everyone in the store.
You want to come back here?
There's something that you need to hear.
It concerns you all.
- Okay?
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I don't know what you people
think you're doing.
You drinking? For Chrissake, Ollie.
Do you want me to report you?
You want to lose your job?
Look, I'm gonna be taking down names,
starting with you.
And I am prepared to file a police report.
- Fine, Bud, write down your names.
- I will.
And in the meantime,
shut the fuck up and listen.
This is Mr. David Drayton.
You need to hear what he's got to say
if you're thinking about leaving.
Go hang out with the ladies, all right?
Listen, don't be scared.
It's okay.
Okay.
This is how it is.
Now, I don't know what this mist is,
but there are things in it
and they're dangerous, like Dan said.
That's right.
That's exactly right.
What kinda things?
I never saw it. It happened too fast.
I got knocked down.
Five us went back in the loading dock.
It was Jim, Myron, Ollie, me,
Norm, the bag boy.
- And we opened the door--
- Where's Norm?
So Norm could go out
and clear the vent for the generator.
Something came out of the mist
and took him.
Took him? What do you mean?
Just killed him.
I mean, dragged him off.
Now, guys, I don't know
what these things are.
All we saw were tentacles.
Tentacles?
Tentacles, he says.
Tentacles from planet X.
No, it's a lie, you know.
All these people do
is just lie each other up.
It's a pile of shit.
Of course it's a lie.
Of course it's a lie, it's lunacy!
And from the look of it, the tentacles
are coming out of the beer cans.
All right, Bud,
don't take our word for it. Go look.
What the hell is that?
It appears we may have a problem
of some magnitude here.
Let me...
help these people.
Let me preach your word.
Let me shine your light.
'Cause they're not all bad.
They can't all be bad.
Some can be saved, can't they?
Yes, some can be brought
to heaven's holy gates through your grace.
I have to believe that,
though I know most people swim
in a lake of fire forever.
If I can save a few,
even one,
then my life will have counted
for something.
I will have pulled my weight,
I will have earned my place at your side,
I will have served a purpose
here on this earth.
Hello?
What?
I just need to use the bathroom.
Okay, well then, have at it.
Ma'am,
I just want you to know that it's okay.
Being scared, I mean.
And, well, if you need a friend, you know,
someone to talk to-
I have a friend. God up above.
I talk to him every day.
Don't you condescend me.
- I'm sorry?
- Not ever.
You don't mock me.
That's not what I was doing.
Look, I tell you what.
The day I need a friend like you,
I'll just have myself a little squat
and shit one out.
Maybe you do believe this.
Maybe they're not lies.
They're delusions, whatever.
The fact remains the evidence here
is flimsy. It's bordering on ludicrous.
Hey, this isn't a courtroom.
You're not arguing a case,
and you're doing nothing but damage,
talking the way you are.
And you can throw as much cow's blood
around the loading dock as you want to.
You still haven't fooled anyone.
Leave it alone, David.
You can't convince some people
there's a fire
even when their hair is burning.
Denial is a powerful thing.
Well, keep talking.
I'll have no part of it,
nor would any thinking person.
Keep thinking, Mr. Lawyer.
There's no defense
against the will of God.
There's no court of appeals in hell.
There's no defense here either,
not even with all the fertilizer
in the world.
Not even if you stack it
as high as you can,
it's still just bags of shit, isn't it?
Those of you who want to
discuss this thing rationally
to find a means of rescue
are welcome to join me.
Those who want to stack dog food,
knock yourselves out.
We got those windows taped up
as best we could,
it should help.
Yeah, I think so.
Duct tape and dog food bags.
That bad?
It's not good.
There's none so blind
as those who will not see.
Open your eyes.
Let the scales fall away.
This has all been written.
Revelations, chapter 15.
"And the temple was filled with smoke
from the glory of God, and from his power.
And no one could enter the temple
until the seven plagues
of the seven angels were completed."
Well, what are you saying?
What are you proposing?
That we all prepare to meet our maker.
Prepare to meet shit.
Lady, your tongue must
be hung in the middle
so that it could waggle at both ends.
No, the end time has come.
Not in flames, but in mist.
- Come here!
- Easy, man!
How about if your ass prepares to meet
my size 10 work boot, how about that?
Hey, there's no call for that.
Yeah, Myron, please,
calm your friend down.
I'm trying to save your soul,
you stupid man.
- Doubters will doubt till the end.
- Don't worry, Billy, it's okay.
A monstrosity did pull that poor boy away.
Things in the mist.
Do you doubt?
Do you?
Then go out.
Go out and say, "How do you do?"
Shut up, lady!
For God's sakes!
Look, you'll have to stop now.
You're scaring the children.
They should be scared.
Yes, they should.
Their beautiful, pure little minds
have been corrupted with lies, lies.
All this talk of a modern God, or no God.
There is one God:
The God of the Israelites.
And he is a stern and vengeful God.
And we have been mocking him far too long.
And now he demands retribution and blood.
It is time to declare yourselves.
Take sides, the saved and the damned.
Read the Good Book.
It calls for expiation.
Blood!
- What?
- Blood.
Little Normie was first,
and now God calls the rest of us.
The bill is due.
It must be paid.
As Abraham prepared
to sacrifice his only son
to prove his love for God, so...
Enough.
Another down payment.
A few more pennies in the jar.
Now that's nice.
See, I can't smack her,
but it's okay for you?
I'm sorry, everybody,
but this lady's perspective
is a little too Old Testament
for my tastes.
They'll come for you.
Maybe tonight when darkness comes.
They'll come tonight.
And they'll take someone else.
See if they don't.
And when they do, you will cry to God,
and you will beg Mother Carmody
to show you the way.
That's fine.
Until then, if you don't shut up,
I'll wrap this tape around your mouth.
You just try it, Ollie Weeks.
And you, bitch.
You hit me again, if you dare.
You'll be on your knees to me
before this is through.
Those of you who aren't locals should know
that Mrs. Carmody is known in town
for being unstable.
No shit.
What was your first clue?
Hi.
Sup, little dude?
How come your friends don't come get us?
They got tanks and stuff, right?
Why can't you just call 'em?
Phones don't work.
But don't you got, like, a radio?
Hey, champ. What's going on?
I want their friends to come rescue us.
They would if they could, pal,
they're stuck here just like us.
But--
Guys, we could use a hand over there.
Yeah, sure thing. Troop, off your asses.
- You all right?
- I don't like that scary lady.
Man, I don't either.
But you know what?
Maybe she's scared too.
You think?
You think Mommy's okay?
Billy...
I'm sorry about the times
I was bad to her.
Hey.
Mommy loves you very much,
and I bet she's fine.
And I promise you,
I'm gonna do everything I can
to get us back to her.
- Okay?
- Okay.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
So we can use the charcoal fluid
and the mops to make torches,
and we've got knives and stuff, God knows.
This may be a silly question, Bud,
but do you happen
to have a gun in the store?
- Here?
- No.
Please, this isn't Los Angeles.
I've got a shotgun in my truck.
I could try for it if you want.
God, I don't think that would be
a good idea, Mr. Cornell.
Hold on.
This gun. My husband's idea.
He's away on business a lot.
It's not even loaded.
Ain't much use unloaded, ma'am.
You know how to use that?
Well, I shot it once on a pistol range,
hit the target a few times.
So, we've got a gun.
Anybody know how to shoot it?
Well, I mean?
I do.
You?
Ollie, please.
Some target shooting.
State champion in '94.
- Hey, you're crazy if you go out there.
- Let us pass! Let us pass, please!
Let's just talk this thing through.
We have, and we made
our decision. We're leaving.
Hey, Mr. Mackey's gonna barbecue
some chicken on the gas grill.
Why don't we just sit down and--
What, and let you keep on talking?
No, I've been in far too many court rooms
to fall for that.
You've already psyched out half a dozen
of my people already.
Your people? What kind of talk is that?
They are people, that's all.
Now, listen, everyone.
We are experiencing some kind of disaster.
I don't know whether
it's man-made or natural,
but I do know that it's definitely
not supernatural, or Biblical.
And no offense, Mrs. Carmody,
but the only way we're gonna
help ourselves is to seek rescue.
We're going out.
Brent, look.
- I'm not discussing this any further.
- I know.
I just want to ask a favor.
Tie this around your waist.
What for?
It'll let us know you got
at least 300 feet.
I'll do it.
Are you throwing in with them?
Me? No thanks.
I think your man there's
a little too tightly wound.
Gonna get somebody killed.
I'm thinking we could use
that shotgun of yours.
I saw where you parked when I pulled in.
Red pickup, right?
Far entrance?
Son, you've got brass balls.
The shells are in the glove compartment.
Drive it back.
All right.
Just see they're paying out this line.
Line's up, I'll cut her loose.
Just so you understand.
Yeah.
You sure there's no way
I can talk you out of this?
David, there's nothing out there.
Nothing in the mist.
What if you were wrong?
Then I guess the joke
would be on me after all.
We're gonna send back help.
You'll die out there, all of you.
Hey, crazy lady.
I believe in God too.
I just don't think he's
the bloodthirsty asshole
you make him out to be.
Well, you take that up with the devil
when you run into him.
Just chat it over at your leisure.
Well, let's strike out
toward the center of town.
Keep it loose.
Nice and easy.
Keep goin'.
Look.
It's goin'.
They're doing good.
Put it down!
Pull!
I'm slipping!
Back up, back up, back up!
Get it off!
Oh, my God.
Cut the rope!
Shut the door!
Now do you see?
Now do you believe?
About a half hour of daylight left.
Guys, how's it going
with these work lights?
We're getting them rigged up, all right.
Yeah, check it out.
All right, all right, save it, save it.
These batteries ain't topped up.
If you turn the lights on,
it's gonna drain them quick.
- How quick?
- Five minutes, maybe 10?
- Yeah, if that.
- Okay.
Emergencies only.
If something gets in the store.
Holy Jesus, you scared the shit outta me.
Sally, I'm sorry, really.
I thought I'd come in and say hi
and see how you were holding up.
- Hi.
Barely, how about you?
I'm worried about my folks, I guess.
You know, they live up on Shorham Road.
That's less than 5 miles from here.
How about yours?
They're out-of-town right now.
They're at my aunt's in Boston, so...
That's lucky.
That means they're okay.
I hope so.
So...
How soon you shippin' out?
A couple weeks.
Scared about going over there?
Yeah.
Hey, Wayne?
How come you never asked me out?
We flirted all through high school.
I know you like me.
So, how come?
I'm stupid, I guess.
Oh, shit, I'm sorry.
Don't be, I just...
I just didn't really want it
to happen like this, you know?
Some shitty locker room at work.
Can we just stay in here a while then?
Okay, just you and me?
The parking lot lamps turned on.
They're on a timer.
Must be a different one that's live.
Maybe we could tie into them somehow.
Get some electricity in here.
That would mean walking out the door.
God!
Oh, my God.
- Billy, Billy.
- David!
Look!
My God.
Bugs?
Not like any I've ever seen.
"They came out of the smoke.
Locusts upon the earth.
And unto them was given power,
even as the scorpions of the earth
have power."
Wow.
Look at those stingers.
Dear God.
Holy shit!
Myron, get the ones in the back.
God, I think they're attracted
to the light.
Look out, look out, look out!
Douse the light!
Look out, look out!
Move, move!
Light, light, light, light, light!
"And there come a voice from the temple,
saying to the seven angels,
'Go your ways,
and pour out the vials of the wrath of God
upon the earth.'"
Ollie, the glass is gonna give!
- Shit.
- Oh, my God.
They turned on all the lights.
- Jim, Myron!
- Fire! Light it! Light it!
Come on, come on!
Whoa!
Sally, look out!
Let me see, sweetheart, let me see.
No, you're gonna be okay,
you're gonna be okay.
Let me see, let me see.
You're fine, you're gonna be okay.
Gimme the lighter, for the fire!
Breathe, stay with me, Sally.
Sweetheart, come on, come on.
Goddamn childproofing sons of bitches.
Shit! Shit!
Shoot it! Shoot it!
I can't! I'll smash the window!
God!
- Go, go!
- Shit!
Get down!
Shit!
- Ollie, you want these lights on or off?
- Leave them on!
Oh, God!
Kill it!
Bring torches!
- We need something to keep 'em out!
- Come on!
Sally!
Where are the goddamn extinguishers?
Get it, get it, get it!
Bring torches!
We need torches at the window!
Plug that hole!
Dad!
Down, down, lay down!
My life.
My life for you,
your will be done.
- No!
- Daddy!
Daddy!
No!
- Billy!
- Daddy!
Billy!
Dad!
- Dad!
- Billy, please!
Billy!
Bring some tape!
Hurry up with the blankets!
It hurts so bad!
Did we get 'em?
Did we get 'em all?
She was right.
She said that it would happen like this.
She said that they would come at night.
She told us someone would die.
Mommy.
It's okay.
It's okay, it's just a dream.
It's just a bad dream.
I want my mommy.
I know.
I know, of course you do.
I want to go home.
Just sleep.
Everything will be better in the morning.
I think he likes you.
Well, I hate that I had to lie to him.
You have kids?
No.
I always wanted to,
but things haven't been working out.
Right now I'm thinking
maybe that's for the best.
I saw creatures fly
into the store tonight.
They shouldn't exist.
I keep thinking I'm gonna
wake up in a rubber room.
You're not alone in that.
We're all right there with you.
This isn't gonna end, is it?
David.
It's Joe. He's getting worse.
Joe.
How you holdin' up, partner?
David, is that you?
Yeah, pal, how are doin'?
It's bad, he's bad.
I didn't know anything
could hurt like this.
If you guys can't help me,
you gotta end it, okay?
Ollie's got that gun, right?
- Right?
- No, no way.
You can't fuck with me on this, bro.
Not with me like this.
I'll do it.
Just give me the gun!
- We're not there yet, okay?
- Please!
Joe, listen.
Pal.
We're gonna work something out.
I just need you to hang in
a little longer, okay?
Can you do that?
Stay with him. I'll be back.
Hattie, I need to go to the bathroom.
Will you watch Billy?
Hattie?
See anything?
The last of those bugs
went away about four.
Dawn's coming.
What's on your mind?
It's Joe.
If we don't get him
on some serious antibiotics
he's gonna die of infection.
Plus he needs painkillers
in the worst way.
All we've got here is liquor and aspirin.
You thinking about going
to the pharmacy next door?
Irene Reppler says they've got Silvadene.
You know, the stuff
they use in burn wards.
- She knows where they keep it.
- Slow down.
You can't actually be
thinking of doing this.
I'm also thinking beyond that.
We have to get out of here.
I mean, permanently.
Why? We've got plenty to eat.
And what happens when one of those things
decides to break through this window?
I'm talking one of the big ones,
like the one that killed Norm.
Yeah, then the flaming torch idea
didn't work so well, did it?
We almost burned the goddamn store down.
It's Hattie.
Here?
Gently now, gently.
One, two, three!
I don't know how long
she was there like that,
lying there next to us.
I thought she was sleeping.
I got my 4-wheel drive.
It's out there.
You're talking about leaving?
Well, we should hit the pharmacy first.
We gotta bring back supplies
for the injured.
I mean, if we don't,
Joe Eagleton's gonna die,
and we can't let that happen.
But after that...
Look, my Land Cruiser
can hold eight people.
I say we drive south
as far as the fuel takes us
and try to keep clear of this mist.
That's it?
- That's the plan?
- That's what I got.
No, you can't mean it.
Not after what happened
to Norton and his group.
No, no, no. Amanda, think.
Norton got over 200 feet from this store,
that's how much rope played out.
I'm parked half that distance from here.
But who knows how far
this mist has spread.
It could be the entire eastern seaboard.
Yeah, it could be the whole world
for all we know.
Wouldn't make us any less dead,
now would it?
We have one gun, how many rounds?
- We got ten left.
- Ten rounds, Jesus.
Okay, so ten.
Want another reason
to get the hell outta here?
I'll give you the best one.
Her.
Mrs. Carmody.
She's our very own Jim Jones.
I'd like to leave before people start
drinking the Kool-Aid.
He's right.
The flakier people get,
the better she's gonna look.
No, I don't buy that.
It's obvious she's nuts.
Look, a few people, maybe. But--
Now I count four.
She's preaching to 'em right now.
By noon, she'll have four more.
By tomorrow night,
when those things come back,
she'll have a congregation,
and then we can start worrying about
who she's gonna sacrifice
to make it all better.
You, Amanda?
My little boy?
He's right.
You don't have much faith in humanity,
do you?
None whatsoever.
I can't accept that.
People are basically good, decent.
My God, David, we're a civilized society.
Sure, as long as the machines are working
and you can dial 9-1 -1.
But you take those things away,
you throw people in the dark,
you scare the shit outta them,
no more rules.
You'll see how primitive they get.
If you scare people badly enough,
you can get 'em to do anything.
They'll turn to whoever promises
a solution.
Or whatever.
Ollie, please, back me up here?
I wish I could.
As a species, we're fundamentally insane.
Put more than two of us in a room,
we pick sides and start dreaming up
reasons to kill one another.
Why'd you think we invented
politics and religion?
Jesus, that's just wrong.
Look, nobody has to
decide anything now, okay?
First things first, the pharmacy.
That'll be our test run.
Okay?
It's all right, Big Bill.
I'll bring you back some comic books.
I don't want them.
I want you to stay here.
I won't be gone long.
It's just next door.
You'll be safe.
Daddy, Daddy, there are things out there.
Things...
Yeah.
There's a lot less of them in the daytime.
They'll wait.
They'll wait in the mist
where you can't see them,
and then when you go
and can't get back in,
they'll come and eat you up!
Daddy, don't go!
I'll be back.
Big Bill, I promise.
I'll be back and then
I'm gonna get you home.
All right?
Together, we're going home.
If something happens, anything at all,
you cut and run.
You get your ass back in here,
for your boy's sake.
If something happens to me,
I want you to take care of Billy
as best as you can,
as long as you can.
The Land Cruiser is yours now.
You get him out of here,
you just keep driving.
Where do you think you're going,
Mr. David Drayton?
Are you so anxious
to make your boy an orphan?
My boy is no concern of yours.
Listen up.
We're going to the pharmacy.
We're gonna bring back some supplies.
Also, there may be people trapped
over there who need help.
Folks, listen!
We're not gonna take any chances.
If there's any trouble, we'll come
straight back here to the supermarket.
And bring the fiends of hell
down on our heads, thank you.
She's right.
You'll make them notice us.
You'll make them come.
Why can't you just
leave well enough alone?
Lady, is this what you call well enough?
You want to stop us,
you better explain to Bobby here
why we're not bringing painkillers
and medicine back for his brother.
No, I'm going. Even if I have to go alone.
You'll die out there, young man.
You'll walk out that door
and be torn to shreds,
and then your hell-bound pride
will have them come get the rest of us.
Yes, they'll come back for all of us,
just like this good lady said.
- Do you want that to happen, people?
- No!
No, no, no!
Well, it is this kind of hubris
that brought the wrath of God
in the first place.
This kind of pride and defiance of the--
Shut up, you miserable buzzard!
You old bitch!
No, no, no, no, no!
Stoning people who piss you off
is perfectly okay.
They do it in the Bible, don't they?
And I got lots of peas.
David, please, if you want to go,
now's the time.
How about it, Army?
Any help from the armed forces?
I'll go.
Jim Grondin.
I had you in school, didn't I?
Yes, me and my sister pauline.
A pair of underachievers.
After you, Jim.
Yes, ma'am.
Shit.
Is that it? That's everybody?
Everybody that's going?
Yes.
Okay. Single file, one by one, all right?
Let's get this thing over with.
Let's go.
- After you.
- Yes.
Stay together.
- Mrs. Carmody, you're not helping.
- I don't care.
- Shut the hell up!
- You shut up!
Save the batteries.
Shit.
They left the doors propped open.
Think something got in?
Let's just get what we need,
get the hell outta here.
Yeah, let's do that.
The meds are over at the end there,
in the cubicle.
Will you not do that?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry!
God.
Where's that Silvadene?
It's over behind David.
In the fridge, check there.
- Silvadene, got it.
- Good.
Ollie, what are we looking for?
- Penicillin.
- Yeah.
Any strong antibiotics.
Pain meds, Vicodin or OxyContin.
OxyContin.
Hydrochloride?
Penicillin.
Guys...
Hurry it up, I hear something.
What?
Something fuckin' weird.
Oh, God.
No.
Oh, no.
Oh, no!
Aw, fuck!
Look, there's another one.
Oh, my God.
No, no, no.
Oh, no, no!
Guys, let's get out of here, now.
Holy shit!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. Help me!
Son of a bitch!
This stuff ain't coming off.
Aw, man.
- He's glued to this fuckin' post.
- Hang in there.
It's our fault.
It's all our fault.
It's really stuck.
I can feel them.
Jesus.
Oh, my God.
Oh, I...
There's more!
There's another one! Hit it!
Ollie, Ollie!
- One over there.
- Ollie, Ollie, there.
There, there.
Shoot, shoot!
Shit.
Where the hell are they?
Bobby!
Bobby, hold on!
Hold on!
Cut the strand!
Help me!
A belt! Who's got a belt?
I've got a belt!
- I got him, I got him.
- Hold on!
Light. Light!
Come on, come on!
Let's go, let's go, let's go,
let's go, let's go!
Watch it, watch it!
All right, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Come on!
Jim, go!
Ollie!
Kill it, kill it!
- Fuckers.
- Oh, no.
- God, he's dead, he's dead!
- Get outta here!
Come on, let's go, let's go!
Come on, come on, come on!
Come on, Drayton, he's dead!
Come on!
Open the door!
Where's Bobby?
Daddy!
Come on, come on, hurry up!
What happened?
They're dead!
They're all dead!
Look at him!
Expiation, because we have seen
that the earth is scourged
with whips and scorpions.
We have seen the earth
vomit forth from her lips
obscenities and profanities
of such nightmare proportions.
And for these evil, lurking spirits
and all these evil people with greed...
How long was I out?
Most of the day.
You just came over here,
lied down, and went to sleep.
Just passed out is more like it.
I just shut down for a while.
I'm sorry.
Expiation!
Expiation! Do you remember yesterday--
How's Joe?
Dead.
Joe died of his burns
while you were asleep.
We were just too late.
I told you this was--
God, I thought I was dreaming her voice.
No dream.
She's getting people whipped up.
That poor girl is dead.
And that boy is burnt in the backroom.
She's got them believing she's a psychic.
She has a direct line to God.
Why wouldn't they?
Woman never shuts up.
Like those speeches Castro used to make.
Ollie says you're thinking of leaving.
I'm in.
No, sorry.
I mean, come on,
you saw what happened to Bobby, Mike.
I won't do that again.
I won't be responsible.
You might want to reconsider that.
What will keep these evil,
these abominations at bay?
What will keep them away?
"The rock will not hide them,
the dead tree give no shelter."
- What will end it, let me hear it?
- Expiation!
- What are we talking about?
- Good, say it again like you mean it.
- Expiation!
Welcome to Sesame Street.
Today's word is "expiation."
Hallelujah, hallelujah!
That boy hasn't been right
since the pharmacy.
His mind's just snapped, gone.
Hasn't even been two days.
Not even two days.
I'm not spending the rest of my life here,
I tell you what.
I can quietly gather up
some bags of groceries
and hide them up
at one of the check stands by the door.
It was your idea, it's your vehicle.
It'll be your call.
I'd rather die out there trying
than in here waiting.
Who will save them? No one.
The rock will not.
I want some idea of what we're up against.
I want to know what this mist is.
I want to talk to the soldiers.
Soldiers? What's that gonna do?
You heard what the MP said
at the pharmacy.
David, I'm not even sure
I knew he was talking.
The situation was insane.
He said he was sorry.
Wasn't that the word he used? Sorry?
That's right.
He said it was their fault, right?
What did he mean by that?
That's what we're gonna find out.
Irene, stay with Billy, please.
Verse 17!
"Poured out his vial into the air,
and there came a great voice
out of the temple of heaven
from the throne saying,
it is done, it is done!
And there were voices
and lighting and thunders
and a great earthquake,
yet as we've not seen."
Yes, come to me!
What?
Where's your friends?
I ain't seen 'em.
Not that big a store.
It's kinda hard to lose.
I ain't seen 'em, I said.
Do I look like their keeper?
What do you want from me?
What do you know about this mist?
I don't know nothin'.
I got nothin' to do with it.
That's not what the MP said
in the pharmacy
before the spiders came out of his skin.
They're not in the store.
The only place we haven't looked
is the loading dock.
Because you know,
you saw the good face of God tonight.
Yes? Tell us.
Here's an old man who has seen.
Yes, he has seen!
And I want to save you,
I want to walk with you
into my father's hands.
Morales.
Donaldson.
Guys?
It's the only place they can be.
What?
Couldn't just disappear.
Look, I told you, okay?
I don't know where they are and I don't...
I didn't think they'd do it.
They said they would do it,
and I told them what the Mp said
at the pharmacy,
and they swore they'd do it,
I just didn't think they would.
Oh, Jesus.
It's the Arrowhead project, isn't it?
This mist.
It's some kind of what, military fuck up?
What were you guys
messing with up there, huh?
We got you now, you sorry son of a bitch!
Get in there! It was them!
It was them what done it to us!
It was them what brung down
the final wrath upon us!
Those two peckerwoods
that he's been with this whole time,
they hung themselves
in the back because they knew.
They knew it all along.
No, he's crazy.
He doesn't know what he's--
- Get on your knees!
- Stay out of it, Drayton.
They heard it too, didn't ya? All of ya!
All about the Arrowhead Project
and all that secret shit
up on the mountain.
That's what brung it down on us.
That's what brung down the wrath of God.
Private Jessup.
It wasn't me.
I'm stationed out there.
I'm not responsible.
- Bullshit.
- Hell, I'm a local!
Most of you people know me.
You!
Stop your chickenshit whining
or I will cut your puling tongue out.
Now you tell us!
Tell us.
Look, look, okay, okay.
I heard stuff.
"Stuff."
Yes, we all heard stuff.
Like, how they thought
that there were other dimensions.
Other worlds all around us
and how they wanted
to try and make a window.
You know, so they could look through
and see what's on the other side.
Well, maybe your window
turned out to be a door, didn't it?
Not mine, those scientists!
- The scientists.
- Yes, the scientists, it wasn't me.
They must've ripped a hole open
by accident,
this other world came
spilling through to ours.
That's what Donaldson was saying to me
right before he killed himself,
I didn't understand the half of it.
It ain't my fault!
Ain't his fault.
No, no, no.
Ain't nothing ever anybody's fault.
But he denies it.
He points the finger.
This Judas in our midst.
Judas!
David!
You, you!
Don't you know by now?
Don't you know the truth?
We are being punished. For what?
For going against the will of God.
For going against
his forbidden rules of old.
Walking on the moon.
Yes, yes!
Or splitting his atoms.
Or stem cells and abortions!
And destroying the secrets of life
that only God above has any right to!
Amen!
Yes, I know.
It is true!
And now we are being punished,
the judgment is being
brought down upon us.
The fiends of hell,
you see they are let loose.
And star Wormwood blazes.
- And it is his fault, yes his--
- No, no!
It is not my fault!
They did it!
They spit in the eye of the almighty!
No!
Get over there!
- No!
- Judas!
String him up!
Stand up, you coward!
Jesus!
- No!
- Stop him!
Feed him to the beast!
Expiation!
Let the abominations smell his blood!
No!
Jesus, wait! David!
Please.
The beast will leave us alone tonight.
Tomorrow...
Tomorrow, we'll just have to wait and see.
Daddy?
I'm sorry I left you, pal.
I won't ever leave you again.
Promise?
You have to give me
your best promise, okay?
Your very best promise.
You can never break it.
Tell me.
Promise you won't let the monsters get me.
Ever, no matter what.
I promise.
I love you, Daddy.
I love you, Billy.
More than anything.
It's dawn.
Hey, pal.
You ready to go home?
Come on.
Okay.
I've got the groceries hidden
at check stand number 2.
Five bags. We can grab 'em
and get out the door.
Okay.
My car's parked in the center lane
of the parking lot, far end.
Whoever gets there first
open up both doors,
and we'll all pile in
as fast as we can, okay?
Let's go.
Stealing food now?
Going out now, Mrs. Carmody.
Please stand aside.
You can't go out, I won't allow it.
Won't allow it?
It's against God's will.
Don't you know that by now?
Haven't I proven myself
again and again and again?
Haven't I shown that I am his vessel?
What's the matter with you?
Don't you believe in God?
No one's interfered with you,
all we're asking for
is the same privilege.
You heard him.
It is these people
who brought this upon us.
They, people who refuse
to bend to the will of God
and claim it privilege.
Sinners in pride.
Yes, haughty.
Privileged!
They mock us, they mock our god,
our faith, our values,
our very lifestyle.
They mock our humility and our piousness.
They piss on us and laugh.
It's from them
the blood of human sacrifice must come.
From them.
The blood of expiation.
You try it.
You fuckin' try it! Come on.
We want the boy.
- You get back!
- We want the boy!
You get back!
Grab that boy! Grab him!
Grab him!
And get the whore too!
Grab her!
Kill them!
Kill them all!
Stay down, stay down, stay down.
I killed her.
Thank you, Ollie.
Let's go.
Get that ice machine
out of the way, please.
- You killed her!
- Come on.
You murdered her!
I wouldn't have shot her, Dave.
Not if there had been any other way.
That's why I said thank you.
Okay.
Okay, then. Let's go!
Get up, Myron!
Come on, we gotta go!
My ankle!
All the way down!
Where are they?
Bud, Myron?
Ambrose!
- I think I broke it!
- Fuck.
Come on, come on, come on!
We gotta go, come on, come on!
They're lost!
- Oh, Jesus. Ollie!
- Ollie!
All that screaming.
Are they out there? Can they see us?
Let me in!
Are we going?
No.
- No, no, no.
- Yeah, yeah.
David.
- David, no.
- Daddy, no.
- David!
- Daddy!
Get back in the car!
- David!
Oh, my God!
Oh, my God.
We gotta go.
I told her I'd fix it.
Front window, broken open.
Tree.
My grandfather's tree.
I'm sorry, David. I'm just so sorry.
Let's...
See how far this fuel takes us, huh?
Maybe we'll get clear of this mist.
Well...
We gave it a good shot.
Nobody could say we didn't.
Nope.
Nobody can say that.
Well...
we've got...
Four.
Four bullets.
But there's five of us.
I'll figure something out.
God!
Come on!
Come on, come on, come on.
Come on, come on!
They're dead, for what?